<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Hop on Hop</title>
    <link>https://hop.apache.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apache Hop on Hop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:44:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hop.apache.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.16 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/11/hop-2.16.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/11/hop-2.16.0/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop community is proud to announce the release of Apache Hop 2.16!
 After another three months of hard work, collaboration, and testing, this release closes 111 tickets by 22 contributors, delivers powerful new capabilities, important integrations, and a series of quality-of-life improvements to make data orchestration even more flexible, robust, and enterprise-ready. We want to extend a heartfelt thank you to every contributor, tester, and user who helped shape this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.15 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/08/hop-2.15.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/08/hop-2.15.0/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop community is proud to announce the release of Apache Hop 2.15!
 After three months of hard work, collaboration, and relentless testing, this release closes 95 tickets by 17 contributors, including important bug fixes, usability improvements, and new features designed to make your data orchestration simpler and more powerful.
 We want to extend a heartfelt thank you to every contributor, tester, and user who helped shape this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.14 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/05/hop-2.14.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/05/hop-2.14.0/</guid>
      <description>After about two months of work on 35 tickets by 7 contributors, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.14.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.14 brings: Updated release cycle Mail server metadata type Various improvements and fixes Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.13 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/04/hop-2.13.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/04/hop-2.13.0/</guid>
      <description>After about two months of work on 84 tickets by 8 contributors, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.13.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.13 brings: Multiple GCP Storage locations MySQL Bulk Loader Transform Various improvements Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.12 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/02/hop-2.12.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2025/02/hop-2.12.0/</guid>
      <description>After about two months of work on 58 tickets by 11 contributors, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.12.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.12 brings: Variable resolvers Various improvements Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.12.0  right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.11 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/12/hop-2.11.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/12/hop-2.11.0/</guid>
      <description>After about two months of work on 109 tickets by 16 contributors, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.11.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.11 brings: 4 NLP and LLM transforms Git improvements Syntax highlighting UI improvements Various changes Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving away from Mattermost</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/10/moving-away-from-mattermost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/10/moving-away-from-mattermost/</guid>
      <description>Hi Everyone,
 As discussed on the mailing lists recently, the Apache Hop community will move away from the Mattermost chat and switch to GitHub Discussions and the ASF Slack workspace for more informal community discussions.
 As discussed in the mailing list thread, there are a couple of reasons to do this:
   The current Mattermost chat isn’t hosted on an offical Apache Hop (sub)domain, which is something we can’t change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.10 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/10/hop-2.10.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/10/hop-2.10.0/</guid>
      <description>After about four months of work on 139 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.10.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.10 brings: Notable bug fixes New Features Block code execution in UDJC and UDJE Ability to configure multiple Azure accounts File Explorer perspective improvements   Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.9 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/05/hop-2.9.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 06:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/05/hop-2.9.0/</guid>
      <description>After more than three months of work on 83 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.9.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.9 brings: Static Schema Static Schema Metadata Type Schema Mapping transform   CrateDB database dialect and bulk loader Various Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.8 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/03/hop-2.8.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 08:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2024/03/hop-2.8.0/</guid>
      <description>After more than three months of work on 79 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.8.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.8 brings: Two new AWS transforms AWS SNS Notify AWS SQS Reader   Various Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.7 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/12/hop-2.7.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 09:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/12/hop-2.7.0/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop PMC is proud to announce the release of version 2.7.0, this release contains 51 tickets and some work that has not been covered by tickets.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.7 brings: Redshift Bulk loader JDBC Driver refactoring Improvements Enhanced JSON Ouput Formula Transform Underline transform names Improved Brazilian   Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.6 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/09/hop-2.6.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 06:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/09/hop-2.6.0/</guid>
      <description>After a summer of hard work on 65 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.6.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.6 brings: Apache Beam Upgrade and doc updates New Google Transforms Google Analytics 4 Google Sheets Input and Output   Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.5 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/06/hop-2.5.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 06:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/06/hop-2.5.0/</guid>
      <description>After another two months of work on exactly 100 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.5.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.5 brings: Apache Beam Upgrade Documentation Beam and Google Dataflow how-to guide Extended Apache Airflow how-to guide Looping how-to guide   Hop Gui Improvements Various changes and improvements Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.4 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/03/hop-2.4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 06:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/03/hop-2.4.0/</guid>
      <description>After another two months of work on 98 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.4.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.4 brings: New Features Improvements Container image Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.4.0  right away.
 Apache Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.3 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/01/hop-2.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 07:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2023/01/hop-2.3.0/</guid>
      <description>After almost two months of work on 82 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.3.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.3 brings: Weblate - New Translation tool Documentation updates Vertica Bulk Loader Community GitHub Issues   or download Hop 2.3.0  right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.2 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/12/hop-2.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 07:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/12/hop-2.2.0/</guid>
      <description>After almost two months of work on over 160 tickets, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.2.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.2 brings: Hop GUI improvements Welcome Dialog A new navigation viewport New data grid toolbars instead of right-click menu Configuration perspective Hop Web   Various component upgrades Apache Beam and Google Dataflow Various Community JIRA   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.1 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/10/hop-2.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 07:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/10/hop-2.1.0/</guid>
      <description>After four and a half months of work, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.1.0.
 A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.1 brings: MongoDB Apache Beam Execution Information Framework and Data Profiling Kubernetes Documentation New plugins Community JIRA   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 2.0 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/06/hop-2.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 07:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/06/hop-2.0.0/</guid>
      <description>After three months of work, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 2.0.0. A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 2.0 brings: Upgrade to Java 11 Chinese translations New transform plugins Apache Avro File Output Apache Doris Bulk Loader Drools Rules Accumulator Drools Rules Executor Formula   Apache Beam upgrade Various Variable Annotations Dimension Lookup/Update new dialog Integration tests   Community JIRA   or download Hop 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 1.2 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/03/hop-1.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/03/hop-1.2.0/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 1.2.0. A huge thank you to everyone involved to made this possible.
 Read on for an overview of what has changed in this release or download Hop 1.2.0 right away.
 Hop Gui Hop Gui continues to evolve. The following list of improvements will make you even more productive in Hop.
   HOP-3298: Hop Gui now remembers the last environment you used when you switch to a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup January 2022</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/02/roundup-2022-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/02/roundup-2022-02/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let&amp;#39;s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here&amp;#39;s the recap for January 2022! Hop Graduation - Apache Software Foundation Press Release Apache Hop 1.1.0 Various Community new Contributions New Committers the Apache Hop Community in numbers   JIRA Activity   Hop Graduation - Apache Software Foundation Press Release Everyone who follows Apache Hop knows we graduated to a Top-Level Project in the final days of 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop 1.1 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/01/hop-1.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/01/hop-1.1.0/</guid>
      <description>After four months of work, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop 1.1.0. A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible.
    
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 1.1 brings: Known Issue Hop Server Docker Apache Beam updates and improvements New and updated plugins Hop Gui improvements Various Community JIRA Download Hop 1.1.0   or download Hop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop Graduates as a Top-Level Project</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/01/hop-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/01/hop-graduation/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop Graduates as a Top-Level Project DISCLAIMER: this is a reprint of the official Apache Software Foundation press release about Hop’s graduation.
   The Apache Software Foundation Announces Open Source data orchestration platform Apache® Hop™ as a Top-Level Project Wilmington, DE, Jan. 18, 2022 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) — The Apache Software Foundation (ASF), the all-volunteer developers, stewards, and incubators of more than 350 Open Source projects and initiatives, announced today Apache® Hop™ as a Top-Level Project (TLP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop Architecture</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/docs/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/docs/architecture/</guid>
      <description>The Hop architecture is very simple in essence: separate out any metadata from runtime code and tooling.
 Doing this, Hop aims to have a minimal installation footprint and wants to be stateless to facilitate execution on a variety of platforms like Spark and Flink, but also in a variety of scenarios like running in different life cycles such as development, test, acceptance, production, unit testing and continuous integration.
 The way these goals are achieved is by allowing orchestration workloads, defined in the broadest possible sense, to be defined as metadata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup December 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/01/roundup-2021-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2022/01/roundup-2021-12/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let&amp;#39;s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here&amp;#39;s the recap for December 2021! Graduation - Hop is now a Top Level Project Hop 1.1.0 preparation Hop 2.0 preparation - Java 11 build is taking shape Lots and lots of improvements and bug fixes New Transform Plugins Hop Server Log4j removed Various   Community JIRA Activity   Graduation - Hop is now a Top Level Project As an early Christmas present, Apache Hop’s graduation was confirmed by that ASF Board on December, 16th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup November 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/12/roundup-2021-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/12/roundup-2021-11/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let&amp;#39;s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here&amp;#39;s the recap for November 2021! Graduation preparation Hop 1.1.0 preparation Hop Server   Neo4j Graph Output Lots and lots of bug fixes and improvements   New plugins Apache Hop 2.0 preparation. Community Hop Mailing lists 3Hx - Hot Hop Hangouts Hop Community   JIRA Activity   Graduation preparation After the release of Hop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 1.0 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/10/hop-1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/10/hop-1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>After more than two years of work, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop (Incubating) 1.0.
    
 This 1.0 release is the result of a massive amount of work by the Apache Hop community.
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 1.0 brings: Code Architecture, cleanup, refactoring Hop GUI and a uniform set of tools Projects and Environments Portable runtimes: design once, run anywhere Unit, Integration and Regression Testing Life cycle management Community   Code Architecture, cleanup, refactoring Since Apache Hop started from the Kettle (Pentaho Data Integration) code base in late 2019, no stone has been left unturned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup July, August 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/09/roundup-2021-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/09/roundup-2021-08/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for July and August 2021!
 Hop 0.99 Release On August 7th, the Hop community released Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.99. As discussed at length in the release announcement, 0.99 is our last stop before Hop 1.0.
 Since we want 1.0 to be as robust as possible, the focus has been on hardening Hop, so we worked hard on finding and fixing as many bugs as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.99 Release Available!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/08/hop-0.99/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/08/hop-0.99/</guid>
      <description>The Hop community is pleased to announce the availability of the Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.99 release, our last stop before Hop 1.0.
 This release contains over 3 months of work. Since our 0.70 release in late April, we’ve seen a lot of activity in a variety of areas. The focus for this release was on hardening Hop to deliver our users the most scalable, robust, documented and tested Hop experience possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup June 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/07/roundup-2021-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/07/roundup-2021-07/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for June 2021!
 Here are some quick links for the restless souls among you: Hop 0.99 Release process VFS Improvements Importer Improvements Hop Web Various 3Hx (Hot Hop Hangout) Sessions Community JIRA Activity     Hop 0.99 Release process We’ve created a couple of release candidate for Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup May 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/06/roundup-2021-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 08:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/06/roundup-2021-06/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for May 2021!
 Here are some quick links for the restless souls among you: Hop 0.99 Release process started Avro Support Various 3Hx (Hot Hop Hangout) Sessions Community JIRA Activity     Hop 0.99 Release process started At the very end of the month (on May, 27th), the release process for Hop 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup April 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/05/roundup-2021-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 08:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/05/roundup-2021-05/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for April 2021!
 Here are some quick links for the restless souls among you: 0.70 release 3Hx (Hot Hop Hangout) Sessions Documentation, Samples, Integration tests Various Hop search Community JIRA Activity     0.70 release On April, 12th, the Hop community release Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.70 Release Available!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/04/release-0.70/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/04/release-0.70/</guid>
      <description>The Hop community is pleased to announce the availability of the Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.70 release.
 This release contains about 2.5 months of work. Since our 0.60 release in late January, we’ve seen a lot of activity in a variety of areas. Hop contributors not only worked on code: we’ve received contributions in artwork, translations, documentation etc. We have more than 45 new plugins, and a total of 223 jira tickets were implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup March 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/04/roundup-2021-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 08:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/04/roundup-2021-04/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for March 2021!
 The list of items we need to cover in the monthly reports continues to grow. Here are some quick links for the restless souls among you: Neo4j integration New file explorer perspective New Metadata Types VFS Drivers New Plugins Various Community JIRA Activity     Neo4j integration We’re really excited to welcome full Neo4j integration in Hop!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup February 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/03/roundup-2021-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/03/roundup-2021-03/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for February 2021!
 We have quite a lot of ground to cover. Here are some quick links for the restless souls among you: Metadata Injection Dark Mode Beam Spark runner improvements New Metadata Types New Plugins Various Community JIRA Tickets     Metadata Injection Metadata injection was added to Hop months ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup January 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/02/roundup-2021-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/02/roundup-2021-02/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let’s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here’s the recap for January 2021!
   Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 Released Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 was released in late January.
 With 0.60 being the first Hop release as an Incubating ASF project, we focused on adopting the &amp;#34;Apache Way&amp;#34;, and made this a source code only release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 released</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/release-0.60/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/release-0.60/</guid>
      <description>Less than three months since Project Hop joined the ASF Incubator (late October 2020), we’re happy to announce Apache Hop 0.60, our first release as an incubating project at the Apache Software Foundation.
   Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 - Source only As stated earlier, one of the main goal of the incubator program is to give projects the time to adopt &amp;#34;The Apache Way&amp;#34;. As such, it took us a bit of time to get the entire process straightened out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup December 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/roundup-2021-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/roundup-2021-01/</guid>
      <description>Welcome in 2021, happy new year!
 While the world has seen its share of problems in 2020, it’s been a roller coaster for Hop!
 Our community continued to work tirelessly in December, even through the holiday period.
 Let’s have a look at what happened in this last burst of productivity for 2020. With this pace of development, 2021 will be a great year for Hop!
 A special shout out to Nicolas Adment, who was on an absolute roll in December!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup November 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/12/roundup-2020-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/12/roundup-2020-12/</guid>
      <description>With 2020 coming to a close, we’ve started preparing for 0.50, which will be our first Apache release. We’ll have more news on that soon!
 At the start of the final month of 2020, let’s have a closer look at what happened at Apache Hop in November.
   Apache Hop Incubation - infrastructure Our migration to the Apache Software Foundation infrastructure is now done. All references to Project Hop have been changed to Apache Hop (Incubating).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup September, October 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/11/roundup-2020-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/11/roundup-2020-11/</guid>
      <description>We’ve had another couple of busy months at Apache Hop. A lot of these changes have been happening in the background, but are very exciting nevertheless. As we’re getting close to finalizing the background work, we’ll soon have more time to work on Hop platform features again.
 Here’s what happened over the last two months.
   Hop joins the Apache Software Foundation, becomes Apache Hop (Incubating)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hop Joins the ASF</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/10/hop-joins-the-asf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/10/hop-joins-the-asf/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop - Incubation Proposal Accepted From the very start with Hop, we haven’t exactly been secretive about our intention to join the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) and donate Project Hop to the ASF as Apache Hop.
 After almost a year of work on Project Hop, we’re very happy to announce we’ve reached a first milestone: the Apache Hop proposal was submitted to the incubator mailing list on September, 9th and has been accepted!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview Release 0.30</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/07/preview-release-0.30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/07/preview-release-0.30/</guid>
      <description>It has been about 2 months since our latest release, and a lot has happened!
 We’re happy to announce to availability of our 0.30 preview release. Please take it for a spin. If you find a bug, please create a bug ticket, if there’s functionality you’d like to see, please create a feature request.
 Direct download here
 Getting Started Guide
 Release Notes: 0.30
 Over 100 tickets have been closed in this release, here we will discuss the major changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup July, August 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/08/roundup-2020-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/08/roundup-2020-08/</guid>
      <description>We released 0.30 in late July, followed by a couple of weeks of slower progress because of summer holidays, but here we are with a roundup for July and August.
 After all the heavy lifting we did in the first half of the year, Project Hop now entered a feature-freeze phase. The focus now is on bug fixing, documentation and hardening the platform. Minor new features may continue to appear, just don’t expect any spectacular new functionality for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup June 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/06/roundup-2020-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/06/roundup-2020-06/</guid>
      <description>Another month has passed, so here we are with a new roundup!
 A lot of work has been done in the last couple of weeks. A huge thanks to Matt, who implemented most of the functionality that was added this month.
 Here’s what happened in June!
   Environments → Projects, Environments and Purposes The environments system, introduced earlier this year, was significantly extended.
   a project is a set of workflows and pipelines with their datasets, tests etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup May 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/05/roundup-2020-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/05/roundup-2020-05/</guid>
      <description>Another month has passed, so here we are with a new roundup!
 In early May, we released version 0.21. Check the release announcement here
 We would like to thank everyone who tested 0.21 and created feature requests and bug tickets. Fixing the bugs and implementing the feature requests will keep us busy for another couple of weeks.
 Apart from the topics discussed below, we have continued to walk the path of major code cleanup and refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview Release 0.21</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/05/preview-release-0.21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/05/preview-release-0.21/</guid>
      <description>In the month since we released 0.10, we’ve added enough functionality to Project Hop for another preview release.
 We’re happy to announce to availability of our 0.21 preview release. Please take it for a spin. If you find a bug, please create a bug ticket, if there’s functionality you’d like to see, please create a feature request.
 Direct download here
 Getting Started Guide
 Release Notes: 0.20, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup April 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/04/roundup-2020-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/04/roundup-2020-04/</guid>
      <description>Another month has passed time for a new roundup! Previous month has been a hectic one, we had our first preview version (0.10) and are currently getting close to releasing 0.20!
 We would like to thank everyone that tested 0.10 and created feature requests and issues, we have not yet been able to solve all of them but so many changes were made we feel like 0.20 is at its place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview Release 0.10</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/04/release-preview-0.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/04/release-preview-0.1/</guid>
      <description>After more than half a year of hard work, we felt the time was right to show the world what we have been working on.
 We’re happy to announce to availability of our 0.10 preview release. Please take it for a spin. If you find a bug, please create a bug ticket, if there’s functionality you’d like to see, please create a feature request.
 Direct download here
 Getting Started Guide</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup March 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/03/roundup-2020-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 12:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/03/roundup-2020-03/</guid>
      <description>A new month, a new roundup! We’re getting very close to a first preview release, expect it to see the light of day in the coming week (don’t haunt us if it’s a week later). We have continued to walk the path of major code cleanup and refactoring. Because we don’t want to bore you with the technical stuff (those interested in the technical stuff come and ask in our #dev channel ) here is an overview of what you can see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup February 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/02/roundup-2020-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 12:38:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/02/roundup-2020-02/</guid>
      <description>Currently we are working on creating a first public preview version of the Hop Orchestration Platform. Expect this version to give you a first overview of what the future of Hop will be offering, we are not following a specific roadmap and are working on all fronts. The main focus of the preview version is UI changes.
 Following items contain the biggest changes but much more is happening.
   UI We are completely rewriting the Hop UI, creating a new experience on how to create data pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/manual/</guid>
      <description>title   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) Maturity Self-Assessment</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/incubator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/incubator/</guid>
      <description>Overview   Tip  Apache Hop graduated in December 2021.     This document is an assessment of the maturity of Apache Hop (Incubating) as an Apache project.
 This document is intended to inform the decision of mentors, community, incubator PMC and ASF Board of Directors) to graduate Hop as a top-level Apache project.
   Maturity model assessment Mentors and community members are encouraged to contribute to this page and comment on it, the following table summarizes project’s self-assessment against the Apache Maturity Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop Security Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/security/</guid>
      <description>Security Vulnerabilities Please note that binary patches are not produced for individual vulnerabilities. To obtain the binary fix for a particular vulnerability you should upgrade to an Apache Hop version where that vulnerability has been fixed.
 For more information about reporting vulnerabilities, see the Apache Security Team page.
   Known Vulnerabilities CVE-2024-24683: fixed in Apache Hop 2.8.0.
 Check the Apache Hop security advisories page for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop is maintained, improved, and extended by code contributions of volunteers. We welcome contributions to Hop, but due to the size of the project and to preserve the high quality of the code base, we follow a contribution process that is explained in this document.
 Please feel free to ask questions at any time. Either send a message in the dev channel on our chatserver or comment on the GitHub issue you are working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-review-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-review-guide/</guid>
      <description>This guide is for all committers and contributors that want to help with reviewing code contributions. Thank you for your effort - good reviews are one the most important and crucial parts of an open source project. This guide should help the community to make reviews such that:
   Contributors have a good contribution experience.
  Our reviews are structured and check all important aspects of a contribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Support</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/commercial/</guid>
      <description>Commercial Support Apache Hop is gaining traction in data orchestration projects across a number of industries. As such, several companies have built products and services around Hop. This page is dedicated to providing descriptions of those offerings and links to more information. Companies are definitely encouraged to update this page directly or send a mail to the Hop PMC with a description of your offerings and we can update the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookies used by this site</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/cookie-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/cookie-info/</guid>
      <description>First Party cookies We use cookies to store website settings they contain following items:
   acceptance of our cookie banner
    Third Party cookies When accepting the cookie banner this website uses cookies to monitor website performance, to do this Google Analytics is used. When your browser supports doNotTrack no cookies are placed on your computer and you will not see a cookie banner from this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/documentation-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/documentation-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Good documentation is crucial for any kind of software. This is especially true for sophisticated software systems such as distributed data processing engines like Apache Hop. The Apache Hop community aims to provide concise, precise, and complete documentation and welcomes any contribution to improve Apache Hop’s documentation.
   Warning  Just like code, documentation is never done. We’re eager to find out how you think our docs can be improved, come discuss with us on our GitHub Discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/download/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop For each release you can find a download of the source code which can be used to build your own version. We recommend using the pre-build binary release, this includes all dependencies required to run and use the software.
 Apache Hop requires Java 17 to be installed on the system. Check [the docs] for more information about the supported JVMs.
 More information can be found in the readme files included in the download archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethos</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/ethos/</guid>
      <description>Community Ethos Great communities make great software!
 Hop wants to be a positive and inclusive community. As an Apache project, we subscribe to the Apache Software Foundation’s Code of Conduct, which is reprinted below.
   Apache Software Foundation Code of Conduct INTRODUCTION This code of conduct applies to all spaces managed by the Apache Software Foundation, including IRC, all public and private mailing lists, issue trackers, wikis, blogs, Twitter, and any other communication channel used by our communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events and User Groups</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/events/</guid>
      <description>User Groups   3Hx - Apache Hop Hot Hop Hangouts 
  Hop User Group Italia
  Grupo de usuarios de Apache Hop en Español 
  Grupo de usuários do Apache Hop em Português 
  Apache Hop em Português no Telegram 
  日本Apache Hop ユーザーグループ (Apache Hop User Group Japan) 
     Events Apache Events  For more information about Apache organised events visit the Apache events page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Issues Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/github-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/github-guide/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Issues is the issue tracker that is being used to track all changes and implementation of new code or documentation in Apache Hop. This document serves to explain the workflow that is used and what can happen after a ticket has been created. The second purpose is to explain what you need to do to create an complete ticket, doing so helps the developers to understand the request and work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hop&#39;s error handling caught a faulty request</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/404/</guid>
      <description>404 - Page not found   The page you requested has yet to be created.
 Return to homepage
   Hop Orchestration Platform Perhaps one of the following pages may be of interest:
 Manual - Download - Contributing
 The Hop Orchestration Platform aims to facilitate all aspects of data and metadata orchestration.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Contribute</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop is developed by an open and friendly community. Everybody is cordially welcome to join the community and contribute to Apache Hop. There are several ways to interact with the community and to contribute to Hop including asking questions, filing bug reports, proposing new features, joining discussions on the mailing lists, contributing code or documentation, improving the website, or testing release candidates.
 What do you want to do? Contributing to Hop goes beyond writing code for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue Priorities</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/priority-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/priority-guide/</guid>
      <description>Issue Priorities Priority 0: Outage This is reserved only for the most critical of bugs halting all development on the project.
 Example Priority 0 issues:
   the build is broken, halting all development
  the website is down
  a vulnerability requires a point release ASAP
    Priority 1: Critical This is considered a high priority. Most P1 bugs should block a release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailing Lists</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</guid>
      <description>Use Hop User List You should post and subscriber to the Hop User List for all your questions on using Hop, or how to do X with Hop etc. If in doubt use this list. The other list, Hop Developer List, is for the Hop team to discus development of the actual Hop project; do not use this list for question on using Hop. Again to re-iterate, use the Hop User List, for you Hop questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/release-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/release-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Apache releases are created through a formal process. The entire process is documented.
 Other useful information:
   ASF Release Management
   Check below for the TL;DR version. As always, we’re eager to hear your feedback!
 What is an Apache Release? Apache Releases are a legal handover of a software project. With each release, a project hands over the ownership of all items in the release to the Apache Software Foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/docs/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/docs/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop team aims to create a new release every 2 to 3 months.
 Here are a few directions that we want to explore for the future of our software:
   Authentication and authorization plugins for various security providers
  VFS:
  Integration with authentication for the VFS plugins, allow VFS configurations per project (instead of the current global Apache Hop configurations)
  S3 compatible object store support through updated AWS libs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/sources/</guid>
      <description>## Web Browsing of git
 To browse via the web:
 https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/hop.git   ## Checking out from git
 git clone https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/hop.git   Only project developers can commit to the git via this method. SSH must be installed on your client machine. Enter your site password when prompted.
 Using github The source code is mirrored to github, so you can also checkout the source code from github, if you are familiar with using github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/support/</guid>
      <description>Getting Help If you are experiencing problems using Hop then please report your problem to our mailing lists. This allows the entire community to help with your problem.
 If you found an issue or have a feature request, pleaae create a ticket in our GitHub Issue Tracker. Adding plenty of details (stack trace, logs, screenshots, …​) makes it easier for the Hop developers to know what you exactly mean, and will allow us to resolve your ticket faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/team/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop developer community is growing rapidly and currently includes contributors employed by many organizations.
 PMC     Name Apache ID Organisation Twitter     Bart Maertens
 bamaer
 know.bi
 
   Brandon Jackson
 usbrandon
  
   Dave Campen
 dcampen
     François Papon
 fpapon
  
   Hans Van Akelyen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/tools/</guid>
      <description>The following tools are used within the Hop community.
   Github
  GitHub Issues
  GitHub Discussions
  Jenkins
  Sonarcloud
  Wiki
  Slack
   GitHub All our source code is publicly available on GitHub, GitHub is a Git repository hosting service, but it adds many of its own features. While Git is a command line tool, GitHub provides a Web-based graphical interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/translation-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/translation-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Translating Apache Hop to your language is an easy and code free contribution that adds a lot of value to our user community. We use an online application called Weblate to help us in translating Hop.
 Hop Translation Website To help translate Hop you can visit https://translate.project-hop.org/
 For more information on how to use Weblate you can read the guides provided on their site.
   Supported languages The current list of languages that can be translated is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/website-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/website-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>The website is the central place and first point of entry for any potentially new user. It needs to contain as much information as possible but not scare away new users with complex structures. This guide explains how to contribute to the website.
  Obtain the documentation sources
  Before you start start working on the documentation…​
  Update or extend the documentation
  Documentation translations</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
