<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Release on Hop</title>
    <link>https://hop.apache.org/categories/Release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Release on Hop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 07:59:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hop.apache.org/categories/Release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 1.0 is available!!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/10/hop-1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/10/hop-1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>After more than two years of work, the Apache Hop community is pleased to announce the general availability of Apache Hop (Incubating) 1.0.
    
 This 1.0 release is the result of a massive amount of work by the Apache Hop community.
 Let&amp;#39;s take a closer look at what Hop 1.0 brings: Code Architecture, cleanup, refactoring Hop GUI and a uniform set of tools Projects and Environments Portable runtimes: design once, run anywhere Unit, Integration and Regression Testing Life cycle management Community   Code Architecture, cleanup, refactoring Since Apache Hop started from the Kettle (Pentaho Data Integration) code base in late 2019, no stone has been left unturned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.99 Release Available!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/08/hop-0.99/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/08/hop-0.99/</guid>
      <description>The Hop community is pleased to announce the availability of the Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.99 release, our last stop before Hop 1.0.
 This release contains over 3 months of work. Since our 0.70 release in late April, we’ve seen a lot of activity in a variety of areas. The focus for this release was on hardening Hop to deliver our users the most scalable, robust, documented and tested Hop experience possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.70 Release Available!</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/04/release-0.70/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/04/release-0.70/</guid>
      <description>The Hop community is pleased to announce the availability of the Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.70 release.
 This release contains about 2.5 months of work. Since our 0.60 release in late January, we’ve seen a lot of activity in a variety of areas. Hop contributors not only worked on code: we’ve received contributions in artwork, translations, documentation etc. We have more than 45 new plugins, and a total of 223 jira tickets were implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 released</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/release-0.60/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/release-0.60/</guid>
      <description>Less than three months since Project Hop joined the ASF Incubator (late October 2020), we’re happy to announce Apache Hop 0.60, our first release as an incubating project at the Apache Software Foundation.
   Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 - Source only As stated earlier, one of the main goal of the incubator program is to give projects the time to adopt &amp;#34;The Apache Way&amp;#34;. As such, it took us a bit of time to get the entire process straightened out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
