<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communities on Hop</title>
    <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communities on Hop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hop.apache.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) Maturity Self-Assessment</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/incubator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/incubator/</guid>
      <description>Overview   Tip  Apache Hop graduated in December 2021.     This document is an assessment of the maturity of Apache Hop (Incubating) as an Apache project.
 This document is intended to inform the decision of mentors, community, incubator PMC and ASF Board of Directors) to graduate Hop as a top-level Apache project.
   Maturity model assessment Mentors and community members are encouraged to contribute to this page and comment on it, the following table summarizes project’s self-assessment against the Apache Maturity Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop is maintained, improved, and extended by code contributions of volunteers. We welcome contributions to Hop, but due to the size of the project and to preserve the high quality of the code base, we follow a contribution process that is explained in this document.
 Please feel free to ask questions at any time. Either send a message in the dev channel on our chatserver or comment on the GitHub issue you are working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-review-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/code-review-guide/</guid>
      <description>This guide is for all committers and contributors that want to help with reviewing code contributions. Thank you for your effort - good reviews are one the most important and crucial parts of an open source project. This guide should help the community to make reviews such that:
   Contributors have a good contribution experience.
  Our reviews are structured and check all important aspects of a contribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Support</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/commercial/</guid>
      <description>Commercial Support Apache Hop is gaining traction in data orchestration projects across a number of industries. As such, several companies have built products and services around Hop. This page is dedicated to providing descriptions of those offerings and links to more information. Companies are definitely encouraged to update this page directly or send a mail to the Hop PMC with a description of your offerings and we can update the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/documentation-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/documentation-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Good documentation is crucial for any kind of software. This is especially true for sophisticated software systems such as distributed data processing engines like Apache Hop. The Apache Hop community aims to provide concise, precise, and complete documentation and welcomes any contribution to improve Apache Hop’s documentation.
   Warning  Just like code, documentation is never done. We’re eager to find out how you think our docs can be improved, come discuss with us on our documentation channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethos</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/ethos/</guid>
      <description>Community Ethos Great communities make great software!
 Hop wants to be a positive and inclusive community. As an Apache project, we subscribe to the Apache Software Foundation’s Code of Conduct, which is reprinted below.
   Apache Software Foundation Code of Conduct INTRODUCTION This code of conduct applies to all spaces managed by the Apache Software Foundation, including IRC, all public and private mailing lists, issue trackers, wikis, blogs, Twitter, and any other communication channel used by our communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events and User Groups</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/events/</guid>
      <description>User Groups   3Hx - Apache Hop Hot Hop Hangouts 
  Hop User Group Italia
  Grupo de usuarios de Apache Hop en Español 
  Grupo de usuários do Apache Hop em Português 
  Apache Hop em Português no Telegram 
  日本Apache Hop ユーザーグループ (Apache Hop User Group Japan) 
     Events Apache Events  For more information about Apache organised events visit the Apache events page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Issues Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/github-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/github-guide/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Issues is the issue tracker that is being used to track all changes and implementation of new code or documentation in Apache Hop. This document serves to explain the workflow that is used and what can happen after a ticket has been created. The second purpose is to explain what you need to do to create an complete ticket, doing so helps the developers to understand the request and work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Contribute</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hop is developed by an open and friendly community. Everybody is cordially welcome to join the community and contribute to Apache Hop. There are several ways to interact with the community and to contribute to Hop including asking questions, filing bug reports, proposing new features, joining discussions on the mailing lists, contributing code or documentation, improving the website, or testing release candidates.
 What do you want to do? Contributing to Hop goes beyond writing code for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue Priorities</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/priority-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/priority-guide/</guid>
      <description>Issue Priorities Priority 0: Outage This is reserved only for the most critical of bugs halting all development on the project.
 Example Priority 0 issues:
   the build is broken, halting all development
  the website is down
  a vulnerability requires a point release ASAP
    Priority 1: Critical This is considered a high priority. Most P1 bugs should block a release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailing Lists</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</guid>
      <description>Use Hop User List You should post and subscriber to the Hop User List for all your questions on using Hop, or how to do X with Hop etc. If in doubt use this list. The other list, Hop Developer List, is for the Hop team to discus development of the actual Hop project; do not use this list for question on using Hop. Again to re-iterate, use the Hop User List, for you Hop questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/release-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/release-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Apache releases are created through a formal process. The entire process is documented.
 Other useful information:
   ASF Release Management
   Check below for the TL;DR version. As always, we’re eager to hear your feedback!
 What is an Apache Release? Apache Releases are a legal handover of a software project. With each release, a project hands over the ownership of all items in the release to the Apache Software Foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/sources/</guid>
      <description>## Web Browsing of git
 To browse via the web:
 https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/hop.git   ## Checking out from git
 git clone https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/hop.git   Only project developers can commit to the git via this method. SSH must be installed on your client machine. Enter your site password when prompted.
 Using github The source code is mirrored to github, so you can also checkout the source code from github, if you are familiar with using github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/support/</guid>
      <description>Getting Help If you are experiencing problems using Hop then please report your problem to our mailing lists. This allows the entire community to help with your problem.
 If you found an issue or have a feature request, pleaae create a ticket in our GitHub Issue Tracker. Adding plenty of details (stack trace, logs, screenshots, …​) makes it easier for the Hop developers to know what you exactly mean, and will allow us to resolve your ticket faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/team/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Hop developer community is growing rapidly and currently includes contributors employed by many organizations.
 PMC     Name Apache ID Organisation Twitter     Bart Maertens
 bamaer
 know.bi
 
   Brandon Jackson
 usbrandon
  
   Dave Campen
 dcampen
     François Papon
 fpapon
  
   Hans Van Akelyen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/tools/</guid>
      <description>The following tools are used within the Hop community.
   Github
  GitHub Issues
  Jenkins
  Sonarcloud
  Wiki
  Mattermost Chat
   GitHub All our source code is publicly available on GitHub, GitHub is a Git repository hosting service, but it adds many of its own features. While Git is a command line tool, GitHub provides a Web-based graphical interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/translation-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/translation-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>Translating Apache Hop to your language is an easy and code free contribution that adds a lot of value to our user community. We use an online application called Weblate to help us in translating Hop.
 Hop Translation Website To help translate Hop you can visit https://translate.project-hop.org/
 For more information on how to use Weblate you can read the guides provided on their site.
   Supported languages The current list of languages that can be translated is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/website-contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/community/contribution-guides/website-contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>The website is the central place and first point of entry for any potentially new user. It needs to contain as much information as possible but not scare away new users with complex structures. This guide explains how to contribute to the website.
  Obtain the documentation sources
  Before you start start working on the documentation…​
  Update or extend the documentation
  Documentation translations</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
