<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Hop on Hop</title>
    <link>https://hop.apache.org/categories/Apache-Hop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apache Hop on Hop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 10:01:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hop.apache.org/categories/Apache-Hop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup February 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/03/roundup-2021-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/03/roundup-2021-03/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let&amp;#8217;s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here&amp;#8217;s the recap for February 2021!
 We have quite a lot of ground to cover. Here are some quick links for the restless souls among you: Metadata Injection Dark Mode Beam Spark runner improvements New Metadata Types New Plugins Various Community JIRA Tickets     Metadata Injection Metadata was added to Hop months ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup January 2021</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/02/roundup-2021-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/02/roundup-2021-02/</guid>
      <description>As always at the start of another new month, let&amp;#8217;s have a look at what happened at Hop over the last month. Here&amp;#8217;s the recap for January 2021!
   Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 Released Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 was released in late January.
 With 0.60 being the first Hop release as an Incubating ASF project, we focused on adopting the &#34;Apache Way&#34;, and made this a source code only release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 released</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/release-0.60/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/release-0.60/</guid>
      <description>Less than three months since Project Hop joined the ASF Incubator (late October 2020), we&amp;#8217;re happy to announce Apache Hop 0.60, our first release as an incubating project at the Apache Software Foundation.
   Apache Hop (Incubating) 0.60 - Source only As stated earlier, one of the main goal of the incubator program is to give projects the time to adopt &#34;The Apache Way&#34;. As such, it took us a bit of time to get the entire process straightened out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup December 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/roundup-2021-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2021/01/roundup-2021-01/</guid>
      <description>Welcome in 2021, happy new year!
 While the world has seen its share of problems in 2020, it&amp;#8217;s been a roller coaster for Hop!
 Our community continued to work tirelessly in December, even through the holiday period.
 Let&amp;#8217;s have a look at what happened in this last burst of productivity for 2020. With this pace of development, 2021 will be a great year for Hop!
 A special shout out to Nicolas Adment, who was on an absolute roll in December!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup November 2020</title>
      <link>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/12/roundup-2020-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hop.apache.org/blog/2020/12/roundup-2020-12/</guid>
      <description>With 2020 coming to a close, we&amp;#8217;ve started preparing for 0.50, which will be our first Apache release. We&amp;#8217;ll have more news on that soon!
 At the start of the final month of 2020, let&amp;#8217;s have a closer look at what happened at Apache Hop in November.
   Apache Hop Incubation - infrastructure Our migration to the Apache Software Foundation infrastructure is now done. All references to Project Hop have been changed to Apache Hop (Incubating).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>